hello everyone my name is greg and i do
stuff welcome everyone to additional
episode to tactics game in unity this is
episode 1 and in this episode we will
figure out how to render our highlights
object on top of the terrain
warning i'm not very proficient with
unity renderer and unity shaders i'm
still learning those systems so take
this method presented in this video with
the grain of salt there might be a
better way to make this
if you know better methods to make what
we're trying to achieve in this video
please let me know in the comments below
in the game
now you will see the highlighter on the
scene but you will see a small problem
with it
it can be invisible or partially visible
because it will be hidden by your
terrain or any other objects
so to make them always clearly visible
we want to make them rendered always
over the terrain
to do this first create a new layer for
the highlight object called highlight
object
assign this layer to the prefab of the
move point
now what we want to do is to tell to
unity in what order it should render its
layers
this will allow us to render the move
point highlight on top of the terrain
open the settings of the project open
graphics
and click on the urp pipeline settings
this will show you currently used
scriptable objects for settings
inside you can see the renderer settings
click on it and it will show you the
renderer settings
these settings define how your renderer
in unity will behave
so what we need to do is to turn off all
the filtering except the terrain don't
worry about everything disappearing
now we want to form the order in which
everything needs to be rendered
and render object for a highlight object
mark them as transparent because our
highlights are transparent
and then we want to override the depths
of the object
depth is a thing which tells to your
gpu what object are being obscured by
other objects
what is in front and what is behind
and we want to tell that our movement
point should always be in front
uncheck right depths
this will turn off the devs writing
then add render object for everything
else both for opaque and transparent
oh yeah i forgot to mark the depths of
your right to be always on
this ensures that your move point will
always be on top of the terrain
this method has its issue for example
look at this case because this cube is
marked as terrain you still can see
through
so you either need to fill it with some
primitive object to obscure vision or
keep it in the mind when making the maps